Madrid, Spain 19/04/1995

nic.tap95@gmail.com nicolastapiasanz.github.io github.com/nicolastapiasanz

+34 686 433 376

Nicolás Tapia Sanz

Videogame & Tool Programmer

Graduated in Videogames Design & Development Degree at ESNE University specialized in programming. Passionate of video games, music and all audiovisual stuff. I have knowledges in programming, design and videogames production. I have worked in several videogames getting involved to the fullest and always trying to take them as far as possible. I have presented my last game, Dead Science, in some of the biggest videogames events of Spain to publishers. Also, I have worked in some research projects for simulation in VR and AI.

ACADEMIC EDUCATION

2015 - 2019: Videogames Design & Development Degree, ESNE (Madrid, Spain) **Programming Specialization**

4th year modules included:

- Advanced 3D Animation (9.65)
- Digital Post-Production (9.60)
- Final Project Degree (9)
- Production II (9)
- Graphics Engines and Plugins (8.85)
- Artificial Intelligence II (8.43)

2nd year modules included:

- Web Videogames Design & Development (10)
- Object-oriented Programming (9.15)
- Visual Programming for Videogames (9)
- Animations & Scripting (8.40)
- Scripts & Storyboarding (8)

3rd year modules included:

- Externships (10)
- Artificial Intelligence (10)
- Operating Environments & Platforms (9.80)
- 3D Animation (9.40)
- Videogames Design: Levels (9.25)
- Videogames Production I (9)
- Videogames Audio (9)

1st year modules included:

- Videogames Technology (10)
- Introduction to the Creative Process (10)
- Basics of Databases (9.1)
- Fundamentals of Programming I (9)
- Programming II (9)

2013 - 2015: Computing Engineer Degree, Universidad Complutense de Madrid (Madrid, Spain) (Not finished)

2011 - 2013: Spanish Bachillerato (A Level), La Salle (Burgos, Spain) (Technology Science Branch)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages Professional Knowledge: C#, C++, Blueprints, HTML, CSS

Basic Knowledge: OpenGL, Java, Javascript, Maxscript, SQL

Videogames Engines Unity Engine, Unreal Engine 4, Construct 3, PlayStation 4 DevKit

Physics Engines PhysX, Bullet, Box2D

Graphics CG, HLSL, GLSL

Other SFML, SDL2, OOP, Visual Studio, Android Studio, VR, AR, GIT, Scrum

Languages Spanish: Native Language

English: Fluent

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

December 2019 - Current: Junior Programmer - Lurtis Rules (Half Trading Day) (Teleworking - Burgos, Spain)

I am teleworking as Junior Programmer in Lurtis Rules with a half trading day. I have worked in an app of AR and geolocalisation developed with Unity and C#. Also, I am working with .NET, Unity and Revit for an architectural project.

July 2019: Virtual Reality Master Class Lecturer / Teacher- ESNE (Madrid, Spain)

Virtual Reality Master Class Teacher in the Videogames Design and Development degree in Digital Post-production subject for the Programming branch students. I taught the basics of virtual reality, existing hardware and its use in engines such as Unity and Unreal Engine 4.

July 2019: Videogames Camp Lecturer / Teacher - ESNE (Madrid, Spain)

Videogames Urban Summer Camp for students between 16-18. Divided in two groups: Basic and Advanced. I taught the basic principles of programming videogames in Construct and Unity respectively to each group. We developed different Top Down, Scroll and Infinite Runner games in 2D.

February 2019 - September 2019: Simulation Programmer - ESNE (Madrid, Spain)

A simulation of population masses in central Madrid for the analysis of the citizen security system. Programmed in Unity and C#. In collaboration with Lenovo and the Madrid City Council.

December 2017 - November 2018: VR Programmer - Observatorio Español del Diseño (OED) (Madrid, Spain)

Development of a VR research project about pedestrians behaviour in situations of running over cars. Simulations of real outrages of vehicles in Madrid. Developed in Unity Engine and C# with Lenovo Explorer headset and HTC Vive Pro.

November 2016 - December 2016: QA Tester - TOUCHVIE (Madrid, Spain)

I tested an app called Dive for Android devices before its launch looking for concrete bugs. Dive is a second screen app to have more information about films or series on TV.

July 2016 - September 2016: Game Designer Support - Gammera Nest (Madrid, Spain)

I worked at the design department for the game *M. The City In The Center Of The World* in collaboration with PlayStation and the Thyssen-Bornemisza Museum for the PS4 console.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

February 2017 - July 2019: Game Producer, Designer, Programmer, BizDev & PR - Unknown Outcome (Madrid, Spain)

University Videogames Studio. We worked in two games: *Dead Science*, a first person exploration and puzzles games in which the main character is a woman who investigates a case of multiple disappearance. For PC and consoles developed in Unreal Engine 4. *Emergency Room*, a 3D overhead game in which the player controls a doctor and a nurse in his daily routine of saving lives. For PC platform and consoles developed in Unity. This project was in the PlayStation First program.

2017, 2018 & 2019: Support Staff at ESNE Stand in AULA Event- ESNE (Madrid, Spain)

May 2018: Best Audio Award at #ESNEGameJamon inLudum Dare 41 with "Warren Of Love" (Madrid, Spain)

Warren Of Love is a game of resource management and shooter in which the player has to control a little warren of rabbits, its food, population and fertilizer. Available at Itch.io.

December 2016 - November 2017: Mechanics & Tools Programmer - Beware The Dev (Madrid, Spain)

University Videogames Studio. I work as a mechanics & tools programmer to improve the workflow of the designers in Unity Engine with C# for the game *Crisantemo*.

April 2017 - May 2017: PlayStation First Program - Sony & ESNE (Madrid, Spain)

This was an University Program developed by Sony to learn how to compile and make videogames with a PS4 DevKit. I had the opportunity to test *Emergency Room* on it and make some improvements for this console.

February 2016 - June 2016: Game Producer, Designer & Programmer - Just Dream (Madrid, Spain)

University Videogame development. Just Dream is a narrative and puzzles game which tells the story of a kid whose biggest dream is to be an astronaut. For Android devices and made with Unity. Available at Play Store.

February 2015 - May 2015: Game Producer, Programmer & Designer - Gravity Cube (Madrid, Spain)

The first videogame I developed by my own. Gravity Cube is an arcade game for Android devices made with Unity in which the player controls the gravity of a cube to avoid obstacles. Available at Play Store.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

| Videogames | Jak & Daxter Saga, God Of War,, Age Of Empires, The Last Of Us, Bloodborne |
|------------|--|
| Sports | Skateboarding, Surfing, Trekking |
| Other | Movies, Series, Music, Fantasy Books, Electric Guitar |
| Jams | Ludum Dare, GameJamOn |